hi my name is you and Slater my talk
嗨，我叫你，我和斯莱特说话
I hold free the functions and it's about
我释放了功能，这是关于
open source service and the FN project
开源服务和FN项目
over the next 20 minutes I'm going to
在接下来的20分钟内，我将
talk about service what it is why it
谈论服务是什么原因
matters why you should choose your
重要的是为什么你应该选择你的
service platform carefully and the FN
服务平台和FN精心
project now my roller Oracle is on a
现在进行项目我的滚筒Oracle正在
cloud architect which means that I work
云架构师，这意味着我工作
with Oracle customers and partners
与Oracle客户和合作伙伴
helping them to design build deploy and
帮助他们设计构建部署并
run applications on the cloud but what I
在云上运行应用程序，但是我
really do and what I've done all the way
真正做到了，我一直都在做
since the start of my career as a
自从我职业生涯开始
research scientist is I solve problems
研究科学家是我解决问题
and solving problems generally boils
解决问题通常会沸腾
down to a few things one of the keys is
归结为几件事，关键之一是
to simplify the problem yeah if you can
简化问题，是的，如果可以的话
make the problem as simple as possible
使问题尽可能简单
then it's easier to solve so you break
那么解决起来就容易了
it down into chunks you restrict the
它分为几块，您限制了
scope so you make sure that you're
范围，以确保您
focusing on the thing that really
专注于真正的事情
matters and something else that's really
很重要的事情
important is choosing the right
重要的是选择正确的
abstraction so for example if you are
抽象，例如，如果您是
looking at geometry and you are
看着几何，你就是
considering you know the surface of
考虑到你知道表面
spheres for instance if you choose the
例如，如果您选择
abstraction of spherical polar
球形极的抽象
coordinates the maths will be much
协调数学会很多
easier and your problem will be much
更容易，你的问题会很多
simpler than if you try to persist with
比您尝试坚持要简单
Cartesian coordinates an abstraction
笛卡尔协调一个抽象
brings me to server lusts
带我到服务器的欲望
so what is service well the CNC F
那么什么是CNC F服务良好的服务
definition is this and I've put some of
定义是这样，我把一些
the words in bold for emphasis
粗体字强调
but serverless computing refers to the
但是无服务器计算是指
concept of building and running
建立和运行的概念
applications that do not require server
不需要服务器的应用程序
management it describes a finer-grained
管理它描述了更细粒度
deployment model where applications
应用程序所在的部署模型
bundled as one or more functions are
捆绑为一个或多个功能是
uploaded to a platform and then executed
上传到平台然后执行
scaled and billed in response to the
缩放和计费以响应
exact demand needed at the moment things
目前所需的确切需求
are going to run when they needed
将在需要时运行
they're not going to be running
他们不会跑
actually waiting for stuff to happen so
实际上等待事情发生，所以
what service is is an abstraction we've
什么服务是我们的抽象
abstracted away the infrastructure in
将基础架构抽象出来
the operations we associate with that
我们与此相关的操作
and if we build an application and run
如果我们构建一个应用程序并运行
it on top of this abstracted
它在这个抽象的顶部
infrastructure we can say that we have a
基础设施，我们可以说我们有一个
service architecture and as developers
服务架构和开发人员
then we can concentrate on delivering
然后我们可以专注于交付
what the business want as functions or
业务需要什么功能
using functions as a service because
使用功能即服务，因为
that's the compute component of service
这是服务的计算组成部分
that's where our business logic is going
这就是我们的业务逻辑要去的地方
to execute so when we're in phase what
执行，所以当我们在阶段
we're doing is we're writing small
我们正在做的是写小
functions because they're small they
功能是因为它们很小
should be easy to write they should be
应该容易写，应该是
easy to get right they should do one
容易正确，他们应该做一个
thing well they should be easy to
好吧，他们应该很容易
understand they should be easy to
了解他们应该很容易
maintain and we're going to run them on
维护，我们将继续运行它们
top of this serverless platform or
此无服务器平台的顶部或
abstracted infrastructure now the
现在抽象的基础架构
University of Berkeley did a report on
伯克利大学做了关于
service computing in March it's well
三月份的服务计算很好
worth looking at I've called out a few
值得一看，我已经讲了一些
points here but they're talking about
点在这里，但他们在谈论
people being attracted to service
人们被服务吸引
functions service computing and
功能服务计算和
especially to functions which they
特别是他们的功能
describe as a new computer abstraction
描述为新的计算机抽象
that promises to become the future of
有望成为未来
cloud computing which may be a bit high
云计算可能会有点高
P but I think what they're getting at is
P，但我认为他们的意思是
that in many cases what we've been doing
在很多情况下，我们一直在做
so far with cloud is taking traditional
到目前为止，云技术已成为传统
applications and moving to them to the
应用程序并将其移至
cloud or creating applications that look
云或创建看起来像的应用程序
like them on the cloud so what we've
像他们在云上一样，所以我们
really done today is reposting with
今天真正完成的工作是与
serverless we actually start to move to
没有服务器，我们实际上开始转向
the point where we develop applications
我们开发应用程序的关键点
for the cloud rather than just ones we
为云而不仅仅是我们
run on it and what do people see well
运行它，人们看到什么
customers see an increase in programming
客户看到编程的增加
productivity and also cost savings
生产率以及节省成本
because you're only consuming resources
因为你只消耗资源
when you need them from a developer's
当您需要开发人员的帮助时
point of view we also avoid this
观点上我们也避免这种情况
scenario where the business acts says to
业务行为说明
do something
做一点事
and before we can do the thing that they
在我们做他们做的事之前
think we should be doing there's a bunch
认为我们应该做一堆
of stuff that we have to do beforehand
我们必须事先做的事情
which frustrates them so serverless
令他们感到沮丧的是无服务器
takes us away from that because that is
使我们远离那个，因为那是
abstracted away so the upsides of
被抽象出来，所以它的优点
service it should make development
服务应该使发展
easier it should improve developer
更容易改善开发人员
productivity which should increase our
生产力应该增加我们
agility as developers that should help
作为开发人员应该提供帮助的敏捷性
make the business more agile and it
使业务更加敏捷
should also reduce the cost to develop
还应该降低开发成本
software and to operate it now if there
软件并立即进行操作（如果有）
are upsides there must be downsides the
有缺点，必须有缺点
number one that I see at the moment is
我目前看到的第一名是
shiny server less it's cool it's hot so
闪亮的服务器少了，凉了，热了，所以
people will use it everywhere and they
人们将在任何地方使用它，他们
are bound to use it in places where it's
一定会在它的地方使用它
not appropriate and then they'll get
不适当的话，他们会得到
upset and blame serverless the other
心烦意乱，指责无服务器的对方
issue is locking you can't necessarily
问题是锁定，您不一定
take something that you've written for
拿一些你写的东西
one service platform and run it on
一个服务平台并在其上运行
another UA may also find that certain
另一个UA也可能会发现
platforms restrict your choice in terms
平台限制您的选择
of languages that you can write your
你可以写你的语言
programs in in terms of where you can
根据您可以在何处进行编程
write your programs and they might be
写你的程序，他们可能是
quite opinionated in inflexible about
固执己见
how you how you abstract your functions
你如何抽象你的功能
and model them so in a sense when you
并在某种意义上为它们建模
choose a service platform
选择一个服务平台
you're almost choosing a cage it might
你几乎要选择一个笼子，它可能
be gilded cage it might be a very very
被镀金的笼子，这可能是一个非常非常
nice cage but before that door shuts and
漂亮的笼子，但在那扇门关上之前
locks I think you need to be sure that
锁，我认为您需要确保
there is enough freedom in that cage to
那个笼子里有足够的自由
keep you happy now I talk to people and
让我开心，现在和别人聊天
I work with people for whom one or some
我与某人或某人一起工作
or all of these freedoms matter they
或所有这些自由很重要
want to be free to choose what language
想要自由选择什么语言
they write their functions in they want
他们在想要的地方写他们的功能
to be free to choose where those
自由选择那些地方
functions run they want to decide how
函数运行，他们想决定如何
they package their applications up they
他们将应用程序打包
don't want to be dependent on a single
不想依赖于一个
vendor they may as individuals or as
供应商，他们可以作为个人或作为
organizations have bitter experience of
组织对
being dependent on
依赖
single vendor and having trouble when
单一供应商，遇到麻烦
that relationship goes bad they may want
他们可能想要那种关系恶化
to be able to move their functions from
能够将其功能从
one cloud to an on-premises environment
一个云到本地环境
to a different cloud or even run in a
到不同的云甚至运行在
decentralized model across multiple
跨多个分散模型
clouds simultaneously they may also have
同时他们可能也有云
privacy concerns you know they don't
您知道的隐私问题不会
necessarily trust all of the public
一定要信任所有人
cloud providers and the ultimate freedom
云提供商和终极自由
that you get or the ultimate freedom
获得或最终的自由
that some of them want is the ability if
他们中有些人想要的是
they decide the platform directory is
他们决定平台目录是
going in a way they don't like is the
他们不喜欢的方式是
ability to fork off and even create
分叉甚至创造的能力
their own serverless platform so what
他们自己的无服务器平台又如何
they really want to do is to free the
他们真正想做的是释放
functions and the way that we're going
功能和我们前进的方式
to free the functions is by moving to
释放功能是通过移动到
open source service now there are a
开源服务现在有一个
number of open source service platforms
开源服务平台数量
out there there's open wisk for example
例如那里有开放的拂尘
there's open fares I'm going to talk
我要谈谈开放票价
about FN because it's the one that I
关于FN，因为这是我
work on that isn't my day job by the way
顺便说一句，那不是我的日常工作
so FN project is an open source service
因此FN项目是一项开源服务
compute platform you can deploy it to
您可以将其部署到的计算平台
any cloud or on-premises or on your
任何云，本地或您的
laptop and we model the functions as
笔记本电脑，我们将功能建模为
containers there's a large number of
容器中有大量的
people working on it I'm a contributor
我正在做的人
we have native support for cloud events
我们对云事件具有本地支持
it's backed by Oracle but independently
它由Oracle支持，但独立
governed with representation at CNCs and
在CNC的代表处进行管理
we have a language based workflow
我们有一个基于语言的工作流程
mechanism called flow now what happens
现在称为流的机制会发生什么
with FN is you take a function and it's
与FN是你要的功能，这是
dependencies and you bake them into a
依赖关系，你把它们烤成一个
docker image which gives you a single
泊坞窗图片
purpose self-contained package for your
专为您准备的独立包装
function the function inside should be
函数里面的函数应该是
stateless any state required needs to be
无状态的任何状态都需要
written out to an external storage or
写出到外部存储或
database because these are ephemeral
数据库，因为这些都是短暂的
they will be run on demand they will
他们将按需运行
exist while they're executing and
在执行过程中存在并且
they will go away and so what your FN
他们会消失，所以你的FN
function looks like is a small chunk of
函数看起来像是一小块
code it's been wrapped into a container
将其包装到容器中的代码
image it takes its input from http
图片从http输入
stream which is basically HTTP over UNIX
流，基本上是UNIX上的HTTP
sockets and any environment variables
套接字和任何环境变量
that are set for that container writes
为该容器写入设置的
back on HTTP stream and it logs to
回到HTTP流，并登录到
syslog so here is hello world in Ruby
syslog，所以这是Ruby中的hello世界
for FM so the first thing we do is
对于FM，我们要做的第一件事是
require the fdk that's the function
需要功能的fdk
development kit I'll talk more about
开发套件，我将详细讨论
that in a sec and then we have our
一秒钟，然后我们有我们的
function here it takes two arguments
这里需要两个参数
context and input context is kind of
上下文和输入上下文是一种
metadata about the invocation the inputs
有关调用输入的元数据
actually the payload in this case we
实际上在这种情况下，有效载荷
check and see if we've been given a name
检查看看我们是否有名字
and say hello name if we have and if not
并打个招呼的名字，如果有的话
we say hello world and then the FD case
我们打招呼的世界，然后是FD案
handle method is called to execute that
调用handle方法执行
function now you can get that
功能现在你可以得到
boilerplate code from the CLI then you
来自CLI的样板代码，然后您
do FN in it - - runtime Ruby in this
在其中执行FN-在此运行时Ruby
case there are others and you give it a
如果有其他人，你给它一个
function name then you deploy the
函数名称，然后部署
function in and into an app which is
在应用程序中以及在其中运行
really kind of like a namespace for
真的有点像一个名称空间
functions and then you can invoke it
函数，然后可以调用它
either using the command line or this
使用命令行或此
ultra memorable and friendly URL what
超难忘的友好网址
actually happens with the deploy is we
实际上发生在部署过程中
do a multi-stage build of the container
对容器进行多阶段构建
when we push it to a registry you can
当我们将其推送到注册表时，您可以
use docker hub if you like and then we
如果您愿意，请使用docker hub，然后我们
create an update function endpoints and
创建一个更新功能端点
the server will lazy load the images
服务器将延迟加载图像
when required F decays function
需要时F衰减功能
development kits they make it much
开发套件，使它们发挥作用
easier to write the functions because as
编写函数更容易，因为
in the example what you do is include
在示例中，您要做的是包括
the package or library or gem or
包装或图书馆或宝石或
whatever your language calls that kind
你的语言叫什么
of thing you write your function against
关于您编写​​函数的事情
that interface and the F DK is in charge
该接口和F DK负责
of providing the input data to the
将输入数据提供给
function and writing out any
功能并写出任何
output and errors at the moment we have
目前我们的输出和错误
F decays as part the project for Python
F作为Python项目的一部分而衰减
Ruby Java node and go dotnet core was
Ruby Java节点和dotnet核心是
recently added and for my sins I
最近加了，为了我的罪过
maintain the Ruby fdk the way the fdk
以fdk的方式维护Ruby fdk
works it opens a socket inside the
工程它打开里面的插座
function container and the FN server
功能容器和FN服务器
connects to that socket the fdk then
然后将fdk连接到该套接字
passes the input from http stream and
传递来自HTTP流的输入并
executes the function giving it the
执行赋予它的功能
input in the context and sends back the
在上下文中输入并发送回
output and logs any errors if you don't
输出并记录任何错误（如果不这样做）
have an FD K for your language that's
为您的语言准备一个FD K
not a problem because it's based on
没问题，因为它基于
docker you've got a couple of options
码头工人，你有几个选择
three actually so the easiest one is
实际上是三个，所以最简单的一个是
bring your own docker file and FN will
带上自己的docker文件，FN将
build a function on that docker file or
在该docker文件上构建函数或
you can bring your own image and FN will
您可以带来自己的形象，FN将
let you build a function based on that
让您基于此构建函数
image the other thing you can do is use
形象您可以做的另一件事是使用
something called hot wrap so if you have
所谓的热包裹，所以如果你有
a program that runs from the command
从命令运行的程序
line you can put that into a docker file
行，您可以将其放入docker文件中
and then you include the hot wrap binary
然后包含热包装二进制文件
as part of the build process and
作为构建过程的一部分，
effectively that will take the input
有效地将输入
from HTTP stream and pass it to your
从HTTP流并将其传递给您
program on standard intake what your
标准摄入量程序
program returns on standard out and send
程序返回标准输出并发送
it back on HTTP stream so from hot wrap
它返回HTTP流，所以从热包装
we go to hot functions so I said our
我们去热门功能，所以我说我们
functions were ephemeral they actually
功能是短暂的，他们实际上
run at least once then once they've run
至少运行一次，然后运行一次
there's a short wait before they
他们经过了短暂的等待
terminate by default it's 30 seconds but
默认终止是30秒，但
that's configurable and if you get
这是可配置的，如果您得到
another invocation before the functions
函数之前的另一个调用
timed out then we'll reuse that
超时，那么我们将重用
container rather than spinning up
容器而不是旋转
another one so the function containers
另一个这样的功能容器
are potentially reusable and the FD ke
具有潜在的可重用性，并且
needs to handle multiple invitations as
需要处理多个邀请，因为
well it also is another good reason to
好吧，这也是另一个很好的理由
make sure your functions are stateless
确保您的功能是无状态的
because if there is a subsequent
因为如果有后续
invocation you don't want something
调用你不需要的东西
hanging around from a previous
从前一个徘徊
that's going to cause problems as I said
就像我说的那样会引起问题
before FN deploy creates a default end
在FN部署创建默认结束之前
point with a non friendly URL that's
用非友好网址指向
used by the CLI and you get one of those
由CLI使用，您将获得其中之一
per function deployment we also have the
根据功能部署，我们还有
concept of triggers so you can use
触发器的概念，因此您可以使用
triggers to have more memorable or
引发更难忘的回忆或
meaningful URLs for humans you can have
对人类有用的有意义的URL
multiple of these so you might have
这些的倍数，所以你可能有
different URLs for different audiences
针对不同受众的不同URL
and you can either create them on the
您可以在
fly using the CLI or in the func Yamma
使用CLI或func Yamma进行飞行
which is the descriptor for the function
这是函数的描述符
the FN server is the API gateway so it
FN服务器是API网关，所以它
manages the apps and functions and as I
管理应用程序和功能
said the app is basically a namespace
说应用程序基本上是一个命名空间
for a bunch of functions and it handles
一堆功能，它处理
the function in vacations it itself runs
假期功能本身运行
as a container and it hosts the function
作为容器，它承载功能
containers using docker in docker that
在docker中使用docker的容器
means that if something goes wrong we've
意味着如果出现问题，我们已经
limited the blast radius we don't affect
限制了我们不影响的爆炸半径
the out of the N it also means that
N之外的意思是
we're not so dependent on what the
我们不是那么依赖
docker version is in the host
Docker版本在主机中
environment because we can have a
环境，因为我们可以拥有
different docker version on the inside
内部不同的docker版本
and it reduces the chance of container
并且减少了容器的机会
name collisions in production which
生产中的名称冲突
would typically you typically run this
通常您通常会运行
on top of Cuban ATS but you have a load
在古巴ATS上，但您负担很重
balancer then you'd have a group of FN
平衡器，那么您将拥有一组FN
server instances you point into a
您指向的服务器实例
container registry to also have an
容器注册表也有一个
object store and data for data database
数据数据库的对象存储和数据
for metadata and the request process
用于元数据和请求过程
goes something like this a request comes
像这样的要求
in you route it to the FN server and
在您将其路由到FN服务器并
then it checks and says have I already
然后它检查并说我已经
got one that's running that'll do if I
有一个正在运行的，如果我
have I'll send the request to that if
我是否可以将请求发送给
not I'll spin it up if I haven't already
不，我会把它旋转起来
got it I'll have to pull it from the
知道了，我必须将其从
repository and then you know send the
存储库，然后您知道发送
business data back to the caller and put
业务数据返回给呼叫者并放入
any information for logs etc into the
日志等的任何信息进入
object store now I said our functions
对象存储现在我说了我们的功能
were small so they're unlikely to be
很小，所以不太可能是
able to do a significant business
能够做大生意
operation in one function so we need a
一个功能的操作，所以我们需要一个
way to
通向
you orchestrate them to work together to
您精心安排他们一起努力
do the the business meaningful tasks and
做有意义的业务任务，
in FN that's something calls flow so
在FN中，这就是所谓的流
it's a promises based orchestration so
这是一个基于承诺的编排
you don't have to learn a new dialect of
您不必学习新的方言
yanil or xml or anything like that and
yanil或xml或类似的东西，以及
what it gives you is a way of composing
它给你的是一种构成方式
your functions together it's flexible
您的功能结合起来非常灵活
you can run the functions in series they
您可以串联运行这些功能
can run in parallel they can run
可以并行运行，可以运行
synchronously Doak and runni
同步Doak和runni
asynchronously and your flow would be
异步，您的流程将是
written in code Java for example eat
用Java语言编写的代码，例如eat
itself is written as a function and
本身是作为一个函数编写的，
deployed as a function within an
作为功​​能部署在
application so if you wanted to you
应用程序，所以如果你想
could put business logic in here but I
可以把业务逻辑放在这里，但我
would really suggest not doing it I
真的建议不要这样做
think the conductor should conduct and
认为指挥应该指挥和
the instrumentalists should play the
乐器演奏者应该演奏
instruments so we can for example use
工具，例如我们可以使用
flow to implement something like a saga
实施传奇的流程
pattern where you've got a business
您经营业务的模式
transaction that's spread across
分散的交易
multiple services you can't use
您无法使用的多种服务
something like two-phase commit so you
像两阶段提交这样的东西，所以你
have a set of local service level
有一套本地服务水平
transactions each one triggers the next
每个交易都会触发下一个交易
event and on failure you would undo a
事件和失败时，您将撤消
previous transaction rather than
以前的交易而不是
rollback so say apply a credit instead
回滚，所以说应用学分
of a debit so we can potentially have FN
借方，所以我们可能有FN
act as our travel agent so in a travel
充当我们的旅行社，所以在旅行中
saga we want to go on holiday we want a
佐贺我们想去度假我们想要一个
hotel and a car and a flight so we start
酒店，汽车和航班，所以我们开始
by booking the flight if that fails
通过预订航班（如果失败）
we'll just stop otherwise we'll book the
我们会停下来，否则我们将预订
hotel if that fails we need to cancel
酒店，如果失败，我们需要取消
the flight as the compensating step
飞行是补偿步骤
otherwise we'll book a car and if that
否则我们会订车，如果那
fails we need to cancel the hotel and
失败，我们需要取消酒店，并且
the flight otherwise we're going on
否则我们要继续
holiday so the code for that would look
假期，所以代码看起来
something like this so we've got a you
这样的事情，所以我们有一个你
can't see down there we've got a flight
看不到那里我们有航班
future up there we've got a hotel future
未来在那里，我们有一个旅馆的未来
we've got a car future and then we
我们有汽车的未来，然后我们
compose these together so we start with
将它们组合在一起，所以我们从
the flight future and then we go to the
未来的飞行，然后我们去
hotel and then the car and if everything
酒店，然后车，如果一切
works we get here a success email
作品，我们收到成功电子邮件
otherwise we're going to exceptionally
否则我们会特别
compose and we're going to first retry
撰写，我们将首先重试
and then cancel each of those functions
然后取消每个功能
in order so at the end will either be
以便最后
going on holiday or everything will be
去度假，否则一切都会
canceled at the moment Flo has language
Flo有语言时取消
support for Java and Python and node go
支持Java和Python以及node go
is in the works and Ruby is on my to-do
正在开发中，而Ruby正在我的工作中
list
清单
so in summary service is a way of using
所以总结服务是一种使用方式
abstraction to simplify what we do it
抽象以简化我们的工作
should enhance developer productivity it
应该提高开发人员的生产力吗
should lower our costs and in many ways
应该降低我们的成本，并在许多方面
it's liable to become the dominant
有可能成为统治者
paradigm for developing new applications
开发新应用程序的范例
but you should choose your platform with
但您应该选择使用
care because it is to some extent a bit
照顾，因为在某种程度上
gilded cage and the FM project is an
镀金的笼子，FM项目是
open source service platform it's
开源服务平台
portable you can run it anywhere it's
便携式，您可以在任何地方运行它
language agnostic it has multiple F DK's
与语言无关的它具有多个F DK
built-in feedback and contributions are
内置的反馈和贡献是
welcome if you want to learn more FM
如果您想了解更多FM，欢迎您
project dot IO we've got a slack
项目点IO我们有些懈怠
workspace the friendly community there
工作区那里的友好社区
you can follow us on Twitter or check us
您可以在Twitter上关注我们或查看我们
out and even contribute on github thank
甚至在github上做出贡献谢谢
you very much my name is un Slater and
你非常我的名字叫联合国斯莱特
if you want to get in touch with me
如果你想和我联系
Twitter is probably the easiest way
Twitter可能是最简单的方法
[Applause]
[掌声]
there are no questions from the audience
听众没有问题
but I have one myself
但是我自己一个人
how do you control the number of docker
你如何控制码头工人的数量
containers our FN server can kind of
我们的FN服务器可以使用的容器
spin up so within the server you can
旋转，以便在服务器内可以
configure you know are you thinking
配置你知道你在想什么
about how much memory and how much
关于多少内存和多少
resources it's going to consume yes you
资源会消耗掉，是的，你
can configure that for the docker
可以为码头工人配置
container that is the FN server okay
FN服务器的容器还可以
thank you so let's thanks again
谢谢，让我们再次感谢
you
您